Jean Ritchie and George Pickow collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Sound Recordings
  - Subseries 16: Uncategorized
    - AFC 2008/005: SR532, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Jean /Flowers Side 1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR533, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: McPeaks.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR534, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Ballad for Easter - copy - Jean Ritchie.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR535, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Not Marry 1-10.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR536, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Jean Ritchie High Hills and Mountains.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR537, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: C.C. reel 1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR538, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: C.C. reel 2.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR539, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Multitrack tape /Jean sings with boys.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR540, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Flower Side #2.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR541, November 1980, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Jean Ritchie, Mike Seeger.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR542, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR543, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR545, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: BBC The Sea.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR546, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR547, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: For record Ritchie family Wash DC.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR548, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Songs for Script I.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR549, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: JR /High Hill /outs mixed.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR550, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, four track; 7 in.
      On the reel: Jean Ritchie concert /safety master /Side A ?? B.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR551, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: ?? Wally Reed ?? Fa Do.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR552, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR553, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
      On the reel: Frank Proffitt /WOP /Thumbstrings, NC.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR554, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR555, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Singing Family.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR556, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR557, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR558, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR559, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR560, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR561, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR562, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Processor's note: no information on the box or reel.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR563, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: master Side A Seeger and Gerrard /Greenhays.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR564, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Side B - tails - master /Seeger and Gerrard / Greenhays.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR565, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR566, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR567, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR568, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR569, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: GR-710-A.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR570, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: GR-710-B.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR571, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Newsworthy [no other information; box discarded as moldy and dirty].
    - AFC 2008/005: SR572, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Bald Headed [no other information; box discarded as moldy and dirty]; possibly "Bald Headed Eagle."
    - AFC 2008/005: SR573, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Blackbirds [no other information; box discarded as moldy and dirty].
    - AFC 2008/005: SR574, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Country Life.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR575, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Drinking.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR576, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips; 10 in.
      no information on box. On the reel: Jean Ritchie /Childhood Songs / master /Side A and B.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR577, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Skyport Reel One; Robinson's Songs /Chris/Jon/P and J.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR578, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Real B /B/T and Tones.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR579, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR580, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR581, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR582, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR583, August 29, 1987, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Flash Gordon 1-6 /"Out There on Their Own: Jean Ritchie" /producer: Joseph Hurley /engineer: Peter Jon Shuler, WBAI-FM, New York, 8/29/87.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR584, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR585, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR586, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR587, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR588, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR589, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR590, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR591, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR592, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Evo /autoharp reel 1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR593, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Evo 15 [15 ips?] /autoharp reel 1.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR594, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR595, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR596, 1977, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Hadassah 77 /Sokole3 [?] /Saffer /NCJW.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR597, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR598, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR599, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR600, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR601, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR602, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR603, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR604, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Greenhays GR707 Reel 1 /Master /Nicholson and Lee /DBX.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR605, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      Greenhays GR707 Reel 2 /Master /Nicholson and Lee /DBX.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR606, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR607, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR608, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, 1/2 track; 10 in.
      Lilly Mae Ledford /Master #1 /Voyager Records.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR609, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips, 1/2 track, stereo; 10 in.
      Lilly Mae Ledford /Master #2 /Voyager Records.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR610, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR611, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR612, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR613, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR614, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR615, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR616, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR617, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR618, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR619, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Side 1 /J. Ritchie /Most Dulcimer /GR714.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR620, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Side B /Ritchie /Most Dulcimer /GR714.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR621, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR622, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR623, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      SR623 and SR624 were received in the same box.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR624, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR625, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR626, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR627, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR628, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
      On the reel: Stewart /Forfar #2.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR629, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 15 ips; 7 in.
      Original ID # E-7 dupe. Sidbury Children's Games.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR630, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 5 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR631, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR632, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR633, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR634, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR635, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1/2 in. width; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR636, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1/2 in. width; 10 in.
      Tape #1
    - AFC 2008/005: SR637, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 1/2 in. width; 10 in.
      Tape #2.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR638, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR639, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR640, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR641, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR642, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR643, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR644, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR645, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR646, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR647, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR648, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR649, 1 sound tape reel: analog, 16 track; 2-inch master tape.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR650, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 7 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR651, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR652, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
    - AFC 2008/005: SR653, 1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
- Series 3: Graphic materials
  Photographic materials have been retained in the same subject groups as they were received from the donor. Some repetition for folder headers and replication of content occurs.
  - Subseries 1: Ritchie family history
    - Ritchie family homestead (Box-folder 120/1)
    - Ritchie cabin (Box-folder 120/2)
    - Edna Ritchie (Box-folder 120/3)
    - Pickow family (Box-folder 120/4)
    - Ritchie family (1/2) (Box-folder 120/5)
    - Ritchie family (2/2) (Box-folder 120/6)
  - Subseries 2: Jean Ritchie
    - Jean: dulcimer and miscellaneous (Box-folder 120/7)
    - Jean Ritchie: slides (Box-folder 120/8)
    - Jean Ritchie: cover for "The Most Dulcimer" (Box-folder 120/9)
    - Jean Ritchie: publicity shots (Box-folder 120/10)
    - Jean Ritchie: portraits (Box-folder 120/11)
    - Jean Ritchie: portraits with church (Box-folder 120/12)
    - Jean Ritchie: portrait, Kentucky, with dulcimer (Box-folder 120/13)
    - Jean Ritchie: receiving an honorary doctorate (Box-folder 120/14)
    - Artistic representations of Jean Ritchie (Box-folder 121/1)
    - Jean: childhood photos (Box-folder 121/2)
    - Jean (1/2), 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 121/3)
    - Jean (2/2), 1940s-1950s (Box-folder 121/4)
    - Jean: unposed photos (young and middle-aged) (1/2) (Box-folder 121/5)
    - Jean: unposed photos (young and middle-aged) (2/2) (Box-folder 121/6)
    - Jean: unposed photos (later years) (Box-folder 121/7)
    - Jean: performing (young and middle-aged) (1/2) (Box-folder 122/1)
    - Jean: performing (young and middle-aged) (2/2) (Box-folder 122/2)
    - Jean: performing (older) (Box-folder 122/3)
    - Jean: performing (Japan tour) (Box-folder 122/4)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: young and middle-aged (1/4) (Box-folder 122/5)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: young and middle-aged (2/4) (Box-folder 122/6)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: young and middle-aged (3/4) (Box-folder 123/1)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: young and middle-aged (4/4) (Box-folder 123/2)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: later years (1/5) (Box-folder 123/3)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: later years (2/5) (Box-folder 123/4)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: later years (3/5) (Box-folder 123/5)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: later years (4/5) (Box-folder 124/1)
    - Publicity photos of Jean: later years (4/5) (Box-folder 124/2)
  - Subseries 3: Photos of George Pickow
    - Photos of George Pickow (1/3) (Box-folder 124/3)
    - Photos of George Pickow (2/3) (Box-folder 124/4)
    - Photos of George Pickow (3/3) (Box-folder 124/5)
  - Subseries 4: Americana
    - Sub-subseries 1: California
      - California (Box-folder 125/1)
      - California - Big Sur - Lonesome Pine, March 1963 (Box-folder 125/2)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Colorado
      - Colorado (Box-folder 125/3)
      - Colorado - lake (Box-folder 125/4)
    - Sub-subseries 3: Connecticut
      - Connecticut (Box-folder 125/5)
      - Connecticut - Mystic Seaport (Box-folder 125/6)
    - Sub-subseries 4: Delaware
      - Delaware (Box-folder 125/7)
    - Sub-subseries 5: Florida
      - Florida, 1977 (Box-folder 125/8)
      - Florida - fauna (Box-folder 125/9)
    - Sub-subseries 6: Hawaii
      - Hawaii (Box-folder 125/10)
    - Sub-subseries 7: Illinois
      - Illinois (1/2) (Box-folder 125/11)
      - Illinois (2/2) (Box-folder 125/12)
      - Illinois - Chicago - cityscapes, 1963 (Box-folder 125/13)
    - Sub-subseries 8: Indiana
      - Indiana - Vevay (Box-folder 125/14)
    - Sub-subseries 9: Kentucky
      - Jean and Kentucky scenes (Box-folder 126/1)
      - Cock fight at stock auction, circa 1953 (Box-folder 126/2)
      - Church service and baptisms (Box-folder 126/3)
      - Levi Jackson Park - moonshine still reproduction, circa 1950 (Box-folder 126/4)
      - Perry County - stock auction (Box-folder 126/5)
      - Quilting, circa 1950 (Box-folder 126/6)
      - "Stiroff"—Mace's Creek Perry County, 1955 (Box-folder 126/7)
      - Ritchie cat toss, in Viper, Kentucky, undated (Box-folder 126/8)
        See box-folder 126/6 for more images of the cat toss.
      - Kentucky and Illinois—"In the Steps of Lincoln" (Box-folder 126/9)
        Possibly used to accompany a newspaper article.
      - Jean Ritchie and three men playing hand bells (Box-folder 126/10)
      - Hindman Settlement School (Box-folder 126/11)
        Includes international photos and materials
      - Hindman Settlement School - crafts (Box-folder 126/12)
      - Hindman Settlement School - outdoors (Box-folder 126/13)
      - Hindman Settlement School - classrooms, 1978, 1983 (Box-folder 126/14)
      - Schoolhouse in Clear Creek, Knott County Kentucky (Box-folder 127/1)
      - Kentucky - university (Box-folder 127/2)
        A digitized print of a scene, printed using an inkjet printer onto paper, and water-spotted.
      - Hindman Methodist Church (Box-folder 127/3)
        Hindman, Kentucky; church services, building new church
      - Quicksand School, November 1979 (Box-folder 127/4)
      - Jean Ritchie - dulcimer lesson (Box-folder 127/5)
      - Crafts - dulcimer making (Box-folder 127/6)
      - Dulcimers - building and playing (Box-folder 127/7)
        Some of these photos may have been used in one of Jean's dulcimer books.
      - Games - maypole (Box-folder 127/8)
      - Coal mining (Box-folder 127/9)
      - Log cabins (Box-folder 127/10)
      - Lexington School for the Deaf (Box-folder 127/11)
      - Homeplace Library - Edna Ritchie (Box-folder 127/12)
        Edna was one of the drivers who also worked as a librarian; the Homeplace Library ran bookmobiles to mountain regions.
      - Kentucky Moonshine Still Museum (Box-folder 127/13)
      - Perry County (Box-folder 127/14)
      - Schoolhouse and schoolroom scenes (Box-folder 127/15)
      - L & N railroad (Box-folder 127/16)
      - Viper (Box-folder 127/17)
      - Hazard (Box-folder 127/18)
      - Farming (Box-folder 128/1)
      - Games - stilts (Box-folder 128/2)
      - Daniel Boone (Box-folder 128/3)
        "Daniel Boone objects" - related to Daniel Boone. Some photos may have accompanied a story by George,
      - Beekeeping (Box-folder 128/4)
      - Christmas (Box-folder 128/5)
      - Baptism (Box-folder 128/6)
      - Crafts - dulcimer making and playing and other instruments (1/3) (Box-folder 128/7)
      - Crafts - dulcimer making and playing and other instruments (2/3) (Box-folder 128/8)
      - Crafts - dulcimer making and playing and other instruments (3/3) (Box-folder 128/9)
      - Crafts - corn shuck dolls (Box-folder 128/10)
      - Kentucky, folk arts, folk musicians, international travel, George's career (1/2) (Box-folder 129/1)
      - Kentucky, folk arts, folk musicians, international travel, George's career (2/2) (Box-folder 129/2)
      - Photos from Dulcimer people (1/3) (Box-folder 129/3)
        Photos that may have been taken for possible inclusion in the book.
      - Photos from Dulcimer people (2/3) (Box-folder 129/4)
        See the description for box-folder 129/3.
      - Photos from Dulcimer people (3/3) (Box-folder 129/5)
      - Photos from Swapping songbook (1/2) (Box-folder 129/6)
      - Photos from Swapping songbook (2/2) (Box-folder 129/7)
        See the description for box-folder 129/6.
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (1/10) (Box-folder 130/1)
        Some photos may be copies or originals of images in other folders.
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (2/10) (Box-folder 130/2)
        See the description for box-folder 130/1.
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (3/10) (Box-folder 130/3)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (4/10) (Box-folder 130/4)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (5/10) (Box-folder 130/5)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (6/10) (Box-folder 130/6)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (7/10) (Box-folder 130/7)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (8/10) (Box-folder 130/8)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (9/10) (Box-folder 131/1)
      - Scenes, crafts, and activities (10/10) (Box-folder 131/2)
    - Sub-subseries 10: Maine
      - Maine (1/2) (Box-folder 131/3)
      - Maine (2/2) (Box-folder 131/4)
    - Sub-subseries 11: Maryland
      - Maryland (Box-folder 131/5)
    - Sub-subseries 12: Massachusetts
      - Boston (Box-folder 131/6)
      - Old Sturbridge (Box-folder 131/7)
      - Provincetown (Box-folder 131/8)
      - Provincetown - boat building and village scenes (Box-folder 131/9)
    - Sub-subseries 13: Michigan
      - Michigan (Box-folder 132/1)
    - Sub-subseries 14: Missouri
      - Missouri - Tom Sawyer - film re-creation, 1946 (Box-folder 132/2)
    - Sub-subseries 15: New England
      - Drying fish (Box-folder 132/3)
      - Sailing ships (Box-folder 132/4)
      - New England and New York - buildings and landscapes (Box-folder 132/5)
    - Sub-subseries 16: New Mexico
      - Taos (Box-folder 132/6)
    - Sub-subseries 17: New York
      - Ambrose light ship - Port of New York (Box-folder 132/7)
      - Broadway (Box-folder 132/8)
      - Bronx - Cabrini (Box-folder 132/9)
      - Brooklyn - Erasmus Hall (Box-folder 132/10)
      - Brooklyn Law School (Box-folder 132/11)
      - Brooklyn or Queens - Curtis Field - police rescue helicopters, circa late 1940s-early 1950s (Box-folder 132/12)
      - Buses and Ferry (Box-folder 132/13)
      - Central Park (Box-folder 132/14)
      - Cooperstown (Box-folder 132/15)
      - Greek Orthodox School (Greek Orthodox Church St. Paul) (Box-folder 132/16)
      - Greenwich Village (Box-folder 132/17)
      - New York Harbor (Box-folder 133/1)
      - Haverstraw (Box-folder 133/2)
      - Henry Street Settlement School (Box-folder 133/3)
      - Long Island University Basketball (Box-folder 133/4)
      - Louis Armstrong School (1/2) (Box-folder 133/5)
      - Louis Armstrong School (2/2) (Box-folder 133/6)
      - Manhasset - North Shore Unitarian Church (Box-folder 133/7)
      - Manhasset - St. Francis Hospital (Box-folder 133/8)
      - New York Harbor, circa 1944 (Box-folder 133/9)
      - New York - various (Box-folder 133/10)
      - Port Washington - parade (Box-folder 133/11)
      - Port Washington Public Library - Louie's Friends Academy (Box-folder 133/12)
      - Roslyn commissioner (Box-folder 134/1)
      - Sands Point art show (Box-folder 134/2)
      - Sands Point - "Falaise" (Guggenheim estate (1/3) (Box-folder 134/3)
      - Sands Point - "Falaise" (Guggenheim estate (2/3) (Box-folder 134/4)
      - Sands Point - "Falaise" (Guggenheim estate (3/3) (Box-folder 134/5)
      - Sands Point - town (Box-folder 134/6)
      - Saratoga (Box-folder 134/7)
      - Staten Island (Box-folder 134/8)
      - New York Stock Exchange, circa 1950 (Box-folder 134/9)
      - Sydenham Hospital ambulance (Box-folder 134/10)
      - Ticonderoga (Box-folder 134/11)
      - Making paper by hand; Bible making (Box-folder 134/12)
      - United Nations (Box-folder 134/13)
      - United Nations School (Box-folder 134/14)
        United Nations school for children of employees, at Parkway Village. Also includes shots of the UN circa early 1950s.
      - Water mill (Box-folder 135/1)
    - Sub-subseries 18: North Carolina
      - North Carolina (Box-folder 135/2)
      - Charleston - Harry Guggenheim's ranch - branding cattle, 1950 (Box-folder 135/3)
      - Island of Bauford, 1950 (Box-folder 135/4)
      - Outer Banks (Box-folder 135/5)
      - Quilting (Box-folder 135/6)
    - Sub-subseries 19: Ohio
      - Hiram College showboat - Vevay (Box-folder 135/7)
    - Sub-subseries 20: Pennsylvania
      - Barn raising, circa 1946 (Box-folder 135/8)
      - Philadelphia - fire department training exercise (Box-folder 135/9)
      - Lancaster - Pretzel Makers, circa 1946 (Box-folder 135/10)
      - Lovefeast at Christmas - Moravian Church, Bethlehem, PA (Box-folder 135/11)
      - Steel mill near Pittsburgh (Box-folder 135/12)
      - Valley Forge (Box-folder 135/13)
    - Sub-subseries 21: South Carolina
      - Cainhoy (Box-folder 135/14)
        The Guggenheim estate, Guggenheim family members, Jean Ritchie and Peter Ritchie, St. Thomas church and the grounds, and related images.
      - Gardens - Middleton Place, Charleston (Box-folder 135/15)
    - Sub-subseries 22: Vermont
      - Vermont (Box-folder 136/1)
        Landscapes and structures.
      - Cutting marble at quarry, circa 1946 (Box-folder 136/2)
      - Slate quarry, circa 1946 (Box-folder 136/3)
    - Sub-subseries 23: Virginia
      - Assateague (Box-folder 136/4)
      - Monticello (Box-folder 136/5)
      - Williamsburg (Box-folder 136/6)
    - Sub-subseries 24: Various United States locations
      - Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 136/7)
        A photo of Jean, a photo of Jean and George together, and two photos of the Lincoln Memorial. See box-folder 167/9.
      - Potomac (Box-folder 136/8)
        A note with the photo: "Potomac where Washington tossed a coin perhaps?" The image (two copies) shows a girl looking down into what may be part of the C and O Canal.
      - Landscapes (Box-folder 136/9)
      - Antiques in the "million dollar showroom" (Box-folder 136/10)
      - Factory making world globes, circa 1947 (Box-folder 136/11)
      - State fair (Box-folder 136/12)
      - Dulcimers and dulcimer making (Box-folder 136/13)
      - Various - misc. (Box-folder 136/14)
      - Hank Levin - dulcimer making - family, circa 1973 (Box-folder 136/15)
      - Various locations and activities (1/5) (Box-folder 136/16)
      - Various locations and activities (2/5) (Box-folder 136/17)
      - Various locations and activities (3/5) (Box-folder 137/1)